hello hello welcome to our annual
WWDC recap with Revenue cat we are going
to be sharing this as a sub Club podcast
as well so for those of you listening on
the podcast this is actually live let's
do a quick round of intros most people
on this podcast probably know me and
Jacob most people in the webinar should
know a little bit about Revenue cat and
us but we'll do a quick round of intros
Charlie tell us a little bit about you
and what you do at Rue cat yeah so I'm
Charlie Chapman I'm a developer advocate
here at Revenue cat and my job is to
come out to events like these or online
and just like talk to developers
understand the pain points they're
having and bring that back to the team
as well as when we come out with new
features explain what it is that we can
do how we can help out your subscription
app Business specifically kind of on the
engineering side of things and Jacob is
CEO of Revenue cat it's kind of boring
for you to tell people what you do
because you the most I don't have a real
job it's a fake job it's never boring
but it's definitely fake uh why don't
you give us your best Revenue cat
elevator pitch well I think Charlie kind
of around it there but yeah we help
developers make more money with the
power of computers we started as an sk1
rapper store kit one rapper which we'll
get to later today but we make software
that helps you do inapp subscriptions
more or less and do it better and
monetize better and be a more successful
app that's our dream and then yeah like
David said my job's made up I do
podcasts that's what I've been doing the
last two days so yeah and then I'm David
Bernard used to be developer Advocate
that got confusing because I'm not
actually a developer so we made up a
name I'm growth Advocate at Revenue cat
I host the sub Club podcast run the
subcl club Community host webinars speak
at Advance I'll be in New York City in
two weeks for app promotion Summit I'll
be intervie I will too actually so I'll
be oh nice yeah I'll be on stage
interviewing the senior VP of growth at
Babel so we'll be in New York City get
in touch if you're in New York or in New
York 4 APS we will be hanging out for a
few days before meeting up with folks so
without further Ado let's get into it
wwc 2024 I personally think the absolute
biggest news of WDC 24 was the
deprecation of everybody's favorite
original API for inap
purchase that's so bad it's storit one
before it was storeit one it was just
storeit storit snit who really wants to
know that stuff but I think snit I've
never heard that one before Google my
Twitter for snor Kit there's a couple
that's like the joke I would make every
four months snor kit more like snor kit
but I do think it's a good time to take
a moment to remember our good friend
storit later known as storit one later
later known as original API for inapp
purchase classic TM but a history lesson
storit didn't come out in iOS 1 it came
out actually come out in iOS 3 I believe
because it wasn't in the very first
iteration of App Store so it was do
2009 that we first got store kit and it
piggybacked this is so beautiful just
the Elegance of technical debt it
piggybacked on the basically technical
foundations of iTunes the old iTunes
buying stuff and the whole App Store
infrastructure originally was built on
the iTunes infrastructure you know Apple
always be shipping which was built on
everybody's favorite very popular web
framework known as web objects if
anybody's ever heard of that they used
to sell it in a box us to know that
because at il1 they used to have it like
in one of the like displays of old Apple
stuff you could buy a box version of web
object so anyway that was the origin of
storit and it all run on Oracle from
what running on Oracle backends yeah
that's awesome you know classic classic
Cutting Edge web technology and yeah you
know what it kind of held up that was
what 2009 to 2024 that's what 15 years
yep 15 years of inapp purchases with
storit they extended it in 20 1 to add
recurring purchases which it was never
designed to do which kind of I'm not too
B out about because it created an
opportunity for me to start a business
but they just kept extending it and
extending it extending it and it's
really is a loadbearing part of the app
economy is this little web objects SDK
and framework and API that's lasted this
long when did Circuit 2 come out like
two years ago three years ago they kind
of announced like hey a newer fresher
like more modern take on how to do
Commerce with an app and then you know
we knew this day would come now they've
deprecated it it doesn't mean it's going
away I actually think it will probably
be around forever like I don't think
they'll be able to fully deprecate it
because there are probably apps out
there don't use Revenue cat that have
like I AP code that's a billion years
old and like maybe someday they will but
like it's going to be a while till they
can really rug that one I don't know
that Apple would ever say this but my
guess would be that something like 80 %
of all like revenue on the App Store
still goes through store kit one cuz so
many big apps trans there's so much
Legacy code there's a big bias there's
gonna be a big bias for the biggest apps
being the oldest right and so like
they're just gonna tend to be on store
kit one and it's a big lift to migrate
from store kit one to store kit 2
there's if you're starting n new store
kit 2 is a much better user experience
but like if you're trying to like mesh
an old system in a new system ask me how
I know it's not super trivial so anyway
just to say goodbye to an old friend it
was good to know you Revenue cat's about
to deprecate kind of our last
dependencies on store kit old store kit
receipts it took us even a few years to
like fully get migrated over we'll still
support the technology and the receipts
and revenue cat will always still work
with probably some degree of both
systems but a pivotal moment for about
12 people uh and us being in that group
but yeah yeah I mean actually there's
probably thousands of Engineers around
the world who deprecated skill sets day
in day out have to deal with stor kid
and all The Oddities and the bugs but
this I'm just really worried what's
gonna happen with like support because
like I can see them breaking stuff in
store kit Original Classic and like
there's just not going to be any
incentive and it's gonna be like oh
upgrade to store kit 2 which is like not
something you can do quickly you know
yeah no they specifically said I mean
and this is them like them deprecating
it as saying like stop using it like
we're not going to stop supporting it
but believe in the if I remember
correctly not still supporting can mean
like we're not going to fix weird Edge
case bugs though no no no but in the if
I remember the slide correctly they
specifically said like will not receive
updates I mean they probably will fix
some critical but if it's like second
order they're just going to be like you
store kit too is the work around right
yeah they're not going to add stuff to
the receipts they're not gonna yeah yeah
so goodbye store kit one so long
farewell well now now when we say store
kit though it's just going mean store
kit too because that was the other thing
they did they rebranded it as original
API for inapp purchase which yeah so
beautifully Apple to name it that but
yeah we'll see you later so personally I
think the second biggest news out of
WWDC was ai ai ai and apparently now
that stands intelligence yes yeah so I
don't want to go too deep today because
I'm actually hoping to schedule a
podcast soon talking about kind of the
future of apps in a post aai world
because I think there are some
interesting discussions to be had but
because it was such big news this week I
did want to touch on it and Jacob I
thought your framing so we recorded a
podcast with Mojo and I thought your
framing was really good that the AI
Revolution is really just a new and the
next app Revolution what what did you
mean by that I was waking up earlier
this year or maybe late last year in
cold sweats because I thought apps were
over I kind of had the feeling that like
oh crap like this Chad gbt thing is
really powerful you could see like a few
more iterations on this and like maybe
you just talk to a thing and it does 90%
of your Computing needs that might still
happen to some degree but I think one
thing that I realized that had come to
before this but kind of became really
clear from Apple's sort of integration
of AI across the entire OS is that the
mobile device and the app Paradigm are
going to be super important for this
next Revolution Computing this like aiiz
of like everything we do because it's on
always it's connected and it has context
and that's like one of the biggest
things that the mobile device has that a
lot of other Computing platforms don't
have is they have context I find this
with like some AI desktop apps I want to
use and stuff is like to get them to
understand context you have to connect
to like a million devices and a million
services for one I don't love giving
random new AI app my like calendar and
email and stuff like that's not secure
right and so like the mobile device has
a ton of advant ages here and then Apple
obviously as the Arbiter you know
they've got this great privacy brand
they do understand this stuff like
Apple's been building CPUs and gpus now
for when did the first AIP series come
out it's probably almost 10 years now
been more than 10 years yeah yeah so
like apple knows how to build Vector
processing chips I assume the new iPhone
will have either dedicated or rebranded
Hardware specifically for running
forward passes on llms and things like
this so like I really think and I guess
to the point that the AI Revolution
really we shouldn't be afraid of it is
that like Apple's teeing us up they're
going to give us like apis to access
their llms the llms will or I say llms
or whatever AI Apple intelligence
features will be able to access your app
we'll talk about app intense a little
bit later but then also I think you'll
be able to dip into all of these
features kind of at the OS level to
supercharge whatever little niche
problem or big Niche problem like you're
solving and yeah I'm a lot less worried
about apps getting left behind by this
because I just think it's so easy to
implement it's accessible the platforms
are going to be pushing it and providing
it to developers I really think like AI
will eliminate a certain number of use
cases that used to maybe could have been
apps like solver there's a bunch of apps
that kind of got semi-locked this week
but like I don't think they're in danger
because even if AI eats the bottom
couple layers of the stack it's also
expanding the surface area of what can
be done with apps right and it's just
creating new opportunities and open AI
app Apple Google like all these like
Foundation model companies are not going
to be able to go after each one of these
apps and that's where developers come in
to like connect this core technology to
like a need so Dave you told me not to
talk about it much but it's gonna be a
good podcast it's gonna be a great
podcast I'm hoping to get Ben Thompson
on actually boy me and Ben we have
history I don't know you and I Jacob I
feel like maybe are well we're
definitely biased and we're very like
app people and I think Ben he even
talked about it recently I think on a
dithering or whatever I think he's kind
of bought into like apps aren't going
anywhere just like the desktop didn't go
anywhere with mobile it's like it just
becomes different use cases like you
were saying but he's a little more AI
Bull and so I think it'd be fun to have
him or someone like him as a kind of
balancing factor to have a deeper
discussion on the future of AI and apps
but I wanted to pass it to Charlie
because I think there are immediate
opportunities with apple intelligence in
iOS 18 especially for Indie developers
who love jumping on that like release
bandwagon to get attention the fall what
are your thoughts on like how developers
can take advantage of this to get
attention in the fall yeah it's been
really weird because watching the
keynote everybody was very very excited
thinking there's all this stuff that we
can hook into but then throughout the
week as we've all been actually digging
into the apis as often is the case with
these things the actual hooks we get in
are a little less full featured from our
perspective as thirdparty developers as
I was expecting that they might be for
example there's that image generation
tool it's basically just a glorified
photo picker from a developer
perspective like we can't do like prompt
engineering I don't think but then the
big one is being able to hook into the
Siri Apple intelligence stuff this is
kind of one of Apple at its best where
they're basically just taking advantage
of the app intense system that they
already had is new this other than Siri
just yeah it's weird this is a thing
that already existed the my like Indie
app I have is a like media app so I
already implemented all of the media app
intent stuff so my understanding is I
don't need to do anything what it does
mean is I get to in September or well
later this year whenever uh these
features actually come out I'll be able
to Market it as if it's a new feature
but I don't think I even have to write
any code for me to plug into it there
are a few new types such as like photo
apps that can do like editing on photos
or something like that I mean this is
going to work really well I feel like
because just seeing how some of the
limit in the chat GPT ecosystem like
some of those limited hooks that they
have with other third parties work
pretty well in the way that llms can
sort of semantically understand app
intense better than Siri ever could
right like you can write a like human
text I don't know if they're gonna in
that's the that's the key because I've
supported Siri in my apps for forever
but how often do people say play this
music from Spotify and they say that the
exact right way ever works right like I
just think of the Larry David sketch of
him yelling at Siri right never ever
works right but if it starts to work
will be in a different world I think
it'll create an interesting new funnel
from like a business perspective the
Paradigm for forever has been like open
app and then you track somebody through
the user experience and now potentially
this shrinks that funnel but then grows
this other one of like your entry point
is a tech Bas very clear intent entry
point into your app and as Apple
intelligence gets better over time it
might not even open your app you can
just provide the app but then how do you
as a developer bring people along and
help them learn about the features your
app has if they're not looking at your
UI I think there's going to be a lot of
new challenges in the future as this
gets more and more fleshed out and
that's I think what developers should be
thinking about over the summer is which
you know so like you you've already
built out some app intents but maybe
spending a couple hours brainstorming
like okay how would somebody think about
for you wanting some form of white noise
dark noise Brown noise whatever and then
are there new contexts that you put in
those intents like I think developers
should be exploring this over the summer
so that they're the most ready they can
be for however it rolls out I think
you're right though Charlie like going
back to my fever dream of like the end
of apps this is a slightly and this is
why this stuff so hard to predict is
like this can really actually be a Big
Boon rather than it is Siri and the OS
maybe taking more of like the
computational load and like not the
computational load so much is the user
interface right like now the interface
of your app becomes less important which
could be negative but the functionality
you provide I mean I think of challenges
like well how do you get somebody to pay
for dark noise now like if they're just
like asking for like where do do you put
a pay wall in the app intent like how do
you do you could hear if somebody asks
for a noise that's premium you just like
pre-roll an audio that's like you
know hey you access this if you want all
these sounds whatever but I mean silly
example but there's going to have to be
rethinking if it becomes like a
significant new channel for like entry
into the app it's going to have to be
rethinking of how we even like monetize
and or the only Channel yeah like does
it become like ASO or SEO where the way
I need to think about my app being used
is like maybe the way it gets into a
White Noise app is you just say hey Siri
calm me down and then like oh being
smart you know what I mean and it's like
you have to learn all these new ways of
telling the system that you can solve
this problem one of the things that lm's
is really good at is just this like
textual human communication right and
like I think that's probably the thing
that's got me most excited and where app
intense never saw them there's app
intense and then there was also like you
could access the search like you could
put stuff up for search inside of Siri
right or inside of like Spotlight
neither of those ever felt like they
were meaningful entry points into apps I
think this might have a chance to
actually fix that so it's exciting yeah
it's so early Apple announces these
things and then it's like later this
year so we don't know how much is coming
in iOS 18 and then we probably will see
kind of some early implementations and
then it's going to evolve over time and
stuff so very early days but it's
exciting so definitely something
developers should be checking out but
speaking of early I wanted to pass it
back to Charlie one more time for Vision
Pro again still very early days what are
your thoughts on how developers should
be thinking about Vision Pro at this
stage even with 2.0 having been
announced a couple days ago I I mean I
think selfishly I was hoping there would
be a little bit more but realistically I
shouldn't have expected there to be that
more this year I think my general
feeling is the same as it's been since
the beginning which is like it's a fun
platform to experiment but understand as
like if you're trying to make a business
this is a really really small audience
still if anything the biggest
announcement was just the fact that
they're opening it up to New Markets
it's definitely still a experimental I
still think of it like it's a publicly
available dev kit and I think that's can
fund it for a very long time
to understand if there's Market here or
not right and they should they shouldn't
like I don't know how long until they
killed the Newton you know what I mean
like it's not unusual for companies to
like roll a new platform and then if it
doesn't pan out in a couple of years
like have to kill it Apple being as well
funded as they are can expend a certain
amount of energy to see if they can find
a niche and get it to take off so oh I'm
a I'm a Vision Pro Bull I think we're
just in the early days I'm with I'm with
Charlie this was a developer kit and
it's going somewhere but it's just going
to take a while to get there it's a
phenomenal experience tell James Cameron
movie if you make a I don't even like
James Cameron movies that much but if
you made an exclusive James Cameron
movie for AP like I'm buying that right
away I tweeted about this a while back I
think what it really is going to take
and I'm kind of shocked Apple hasn't and
maybe this is kind of their patience as
well right is that they know it's a
developer kit now maybe there's going to
be a vision that's not a Vision Pro
that's going to be kind of more consumer
friendly so maybe they're kind of
holding their cards a little bit like
they want want to make that you would
want to make Avatar 3 exclusive for AP
now until there's like a thousand device
that's more consumer friendly the
platform is more mature all those kind
of things it has to be it has to be the
price of a nice TV which is like $500
$800 right so I think it's going
somewhere but it's still early days and
so I mean the way I continue to think
about it is if you have the bandwidth
and kind of the financial backing to be
able to explore things that don't
require an immediate return on
investment it's a fun fun place to play
like there's cool games there's awesome
experiences like people are doing really
cool stuff on it and and the immersion
and like apple immersive videos like
it's really cool but it's just early so
if you can afford to play play but it's
not a like build a business on it yet is
my perspective exactly I did a
presentation at a conference earlier
this year talking about it and the big
banner slide was this is not a gold rush
trying to articulate that yeah yeah this
isn't the original iPhone or the
original iPad don't play that same
Playbook there and expect to come out
getting the pot of gold at the end like
you did in those eras do you remember
off the top of your head at least
directionally what the numbers were
iPhone launch then iPad launch then
watch launch cuz you're slides in that
anybody who hasn't watched Charlie's
presentation if you're curious about
Vision Pro he did a phenomenal
presentation I watched it on the flights
I did this last month is really good so
yeah you shared like the at launch of
these different platforms the scale was
just so different yeah the iPhone was
bigger than I was expecting whenever I
like started running the numbers and
then the iPad was just at a completely
different scale yeah and the the Apple
watch was still bigger than the iPhone
it was just seen as a failure because
the expectation was so high and then you
see the Vision Pro number and I mean
none of this is super surprising but
seeing it graphically laid out like that
was a good reminder of what to actually
expect if you're trying to run a
business on this app store yeah and then
like orders of magnitude it's like
hundreds of thousands
of if for people on the podcast I'm like
holding up my fingers like with a little
teeny tiny sliver of like Vision Pro
hundreds of thousands of units and then
the iPhone even was like tens of
millions of units by the time the App
Store really started taking off and even
at launch I believe it was maybe even
over 10 million and at least within the
first year it was in the tens of
millions and then iPad was like tens of
millions very quickly and so it's like
you just see this tiny little sliver and
Charlie's charts from his presentation
compared to like these massive platform
launches that were the kind of more gold
rushy so anyways early days and a lot of
opportunity but not something especially
business relevant today so I'm going to
move on this is going to be me
monologuing a bit but Charlie and Jacob
I'll kind of pause here and there for
youall to jump in but Apple announc a
ton of stuff and since this is a recap
webinar and I spent the most time deep
diving into all this stuff I'm G to go
through and just kind of talk about
because they did a lot of cool stuff so
a lot of this is in the there's a what's
new in app store connect wwc video if
you want to go more in depth there's
like five or six videos we'll be
referencing in talking through this
stuff that you can go watch for more
detail but I know tons of folks aren't
going to sit down and watch the whole
video so I'm going to give the Highlight
Reel of what Apple announced in app
store connect you can nominate your app
for featuring now and it's cool because
it's like a whole new UI because you get
to actually say when these new features
are launching when your 3.0 is launching
when your new app is launching in and
then you get to pitch it to Apple in a
more directed way so that's a cool new
feature of App Store connect and an
opportunity to get your app in front of
apple and hopefully get it featured
similarly there's like marketing asset
creation App Store connect now I first
read about this on the web before I saw
the video demo so I was like ah like any
designer is going to be able to like
throw something together I was like ah
it'll just be for Indies but then I saw
in the video it's like in apps or
connect you can generate these like
promotional images that that are
animated and have like these glossy
little thing like apple actually did a
really good job with this so not just
Indies I think are going to use this
it's like you can go into App Store
connect and like build these little
promotional images that like play really
well you have some ability to like
customize them and stuff or it minimally
I think it's just like text
customization and then it kind of autog
generates a lot of this like animations
and stuff but it I mean it looks really
nice I it looks like you kind of hired
somebody yeah but if they all look like
that it's not going to be differentiated
right so but but how many people are
going to see multiple of these right
it's like you're targeting your audience
with a specific thing and maybe it's
good that they're similar it's like are
these not like the assets that get used
in like promo banners and stuff like
that no it's like a different external
it's like for you to be like hey I got
promoted here's like about it or put it
in your your distribution yeah yeah
that's cool that's a nice it's really
nice that's just a gift from Apple thank
you yeah thank you doing something with
that 30% I'm
glad and then one of the cool things too
is that Apple will Now notify you when
you get featured and then they create
special artwork uh highlight that you
got featured that's so nice there's
certain platforms you would subscribe to
almost just for that just to know where
and when you were featured right uh so
do you know David my understanding from
the conversations I've had here is that
that's only for app of the day does that
also include the different lists that
you get in throughout the store and
different countries I did not see
details on that so TBD but I would
imagine if it is currently just for app
of the day they'll expand it over time
to yeah I hope so cuz that's the
challenge is like especially as an indie
when you see the sudden Spike and you're
trying to figure out what happened uh
it's it's like oh in Turkey there's a
list in on the Today tab but it's not
necessarily app of the day and finding
those is a real pain so that would be
sweet if we could get more clear
notifications on that yeah but to
Jacob's Point these thirdparty tools
that tell you like app figures has a
great view you can go into to see where
all the different countries you're
featur featured in and what lists you're
featured in and stuff I don't think
those are going away yet but it's cool
that Apple's moving this direction and
then has these like custom artwork that
you can share to promote that you got
featured by Apple so cool little detail
deep links for custom product pages this
is another really cool one I don't know
that a lot of kind of smaller apps have
been experimenting with this because
it's been more of a bigger apps create
an ad highlighting like Strava they do
both running and they do cycling and so
if you create an ad more focused on
running you want them to land on the app
store and see stuff more about running
than cycling and so big apps have been
doing this but I think Apple's just
making it easier and easier to do this
stuff where if your app has multiple
primary use cases different features you
can create these custom product pages
and this has been around for a while to
creating custom product pages but now
when somebody buys through that custom
product page it can deep link into your
app to give a customize onboarding so
straa might say okay now you saw an ad
about running you saw the App Store
screenshots about running and now when
you open the app you're going to get the
runner onboarding not the cycling
onboarding again just another really
cool expansion of the capabilities of
the App Store that provides a better way
for you to customize that whole end to
end experience and this is you know a
longtime complaint of the App Store it's
a big black box you have very little
control this is Apple just ticking away
like giving us more control of how we
want our prospects and customers to
experience our app on the app store and
then once they have then deep linking
into the app with more customized
experiences so super cool and then it is
coming to App Store search ads and this
I think was announced before that so now
you'll be able to create different crust
and product pages for different search
ad terms so again Strava it's like if
they're buying a bunch of running Search
terms they don't want to show their
normal product page they want to show
the custom product page and then again
they want to link from that custom
product page to a custom onboarding so
really powerful stuff does that make
like attribution easier that's what I
was just thinking yeah I mean I know
there's like ways that some people are
doing this but this almost feels like an
official kind of API for that yeah it
depends on how many of these you can
create right yeah that's true that's
true but even so if you're just trying
to run like some localized or you could
create some broad buckets that would be
helpful yeah and this is something I had
been looking at and I haven't dug deep
into it and this maybe something we
should investigate write a blog post or
something but I do think it gives
opportunity to at least like more
broadly get some understanding of how
and why your customers are coming in but
they're trying to prevent tracking and
so if only 10 people click on a specific
link to a specific custom product page
there's probably still going to be some
level of an anonymity but if they're
deep linking into your app I don't know
exactly how Apple could enforce that
because you could probably just be able
to like pull that out but I think it's
to Jacob's point is that even if only
four people click on a link to this
specific custom product page you can't
create like 50,000 product pages to
where you can individually identify but
even if you can create it yeah yeah like
I'm looking at it now yeah it uses deep
links or Universal links so like you can
basically assign a universal link to any
of your which is interesting because I
don't know I guess they cach that when
you install and then on first open like
you'll get a Handler to handle that
Universal link that's actually really
powerful very cool stuff we should
definitely dig deeper and write some
content around this there are some cool
updates to test fly the kind of
long abandoned barely moved product you
can now send your public invite links
and then they land on more of like an
app store Page like it has screenshots
and explanation of your app and things
like that so when you're trying to
recruit testers the experience of
recruiting testers has been pretty poor
so they made some pretty big
improvements to that you can set
criteria for that as well so if you like
really need people on iOS 15 because
you're making sure you have your
backward compatibility you can say only
allow people to join if they're still on
iOS 15 or something like that so and
then you actually get stats on the
enrollment so like how many people
landed on your page how many actually
enrolled like how many met the criteria
how many didn't meet their criteria so
kind of cool I would love to see them
invest more in testl personally the
features I want to see is more around
like group management and like being
able B to like email the users on the
beta with testing notes and like there's
a lot of stuff they could do to continue
improving test flight but hey again a
nice step forward a nice little
enhancement they added there sorry did
go back a topic 35 you can have 35
custom landing pages it's not infinite
and that kind of achieves what Apple's
vision is on and we'll talk about add
attribution later which is like some
amount of attribution but like what they
really just don't want is you to be able
to like narrow down to a person and so
it's a pretty good way to to achieve
that so you can imagine setting up 10
campaigns or 20 campaigns that each link
to a different maybe even the page is
the same but then you handle that deep
link through to your app and now you
have a way to like attribute what
campaign they came from which is kind of
interesting so yeah very cool next upep
was reduced screenshot requirements that
was the title of the section and they
could have just this could have been the
only thing they announced and I think it
would have been a win was this the third
most important thing announced at wwc2
yeah I mean this is this is where you
wish you had the old session CU there
would be cheering in the the room so so
the gist of this is that for those who
have not had the pleasure of working an
app store connect still to this day you
have to upload different iPhone size
screenshots for different sized iPhones
I think the latest requirement is
luckily you don't have to do that across
across languages do you yeah oh you do
oh my
God so it's like every language you want
to support I think it's two or three
different iPhone sizes and two or three
iPad sizes what they did now and I think
this is a like coming this fall thing as
well or coming later this year thing is
that when you go into App Store connect
you can have one set of iPhone
screenshots per language and then one
set of iPad screenshots per language so
just massively reduced complexity and
there's all these tools that do this for
you butan had stuff built into to do
this right like there's yeah there's all
kinds of automations but but I've always
generating them was a pain in the butt
like how do you make that many images
right and so for people who like
automate this and just do like really
simple screenshots and there's tools
that help you automate this but like all
my screenshots are in sketch and so I
always have to like do multiple sizes
and the sketch fil is insane luckily
luckily App Store connect is really
responsive and fast so it makes it
really easy right I can't tell you how
many times I tried to submit and it's
like you didn't do this and I'm like did
what and then it's like three layers
deep is like oh I didn't update one
screenshot size in one language or they
use web objects in Oracle so you know it
must be
fast I don't even know if they still do
I just like I hope they don't I love to
give the Apple backend teams a hard time
this is another podcast I'd love to do
an ex Apple employee if they're ready to
just kind of
like like those Anonymous like True
Crime was like like shadowed out yeah
that's when we actually used the Java
framework that was 30 years old to you
know that'd be good I'd love that a
history of App Store back end would be a
fascinating oh my God to a small
audience David some stories just
shouldn't be told that's one that we're
gonna probably lose to history but it's
okay all right App Store search
enhancements this one's another cool one
again like lots of little things
stacking up to just make things better
for the App Store and developers so
currently if you go to the App Store and
go to the search tab you get kind of
like this customized view where it's
like suggested searches and suggested
apps and things like that which is
really cool that's been around a few
years so now though when you tap into
the search field because currently if
you tap into the search field nothing
changes so now coming this fall in iOS
18 when you tap into the search field it
actually gives you recent searches that
you can clear and then it gives you
suggested searches like personalized
suggested searches it's just another
cool thing where when somebody's going
to search and they probably have
something in mind but if they don't or
if they get distracted it's going to
hopefully help more apps get discovered
by people spending more time in Search
and having more personalized
recommendations all that kind of stuff
so another cool thing there's now
Enterprise program API is not super
applicable to us but again another cool
thing Apple's doing is allowing more
direct access to Enterprise feature so
if you're doing any kind of Enterprise
distribution less painful through the
API
App Store analytics API this is kind of
cool you can now get a lot more details
about your app store performance through
the analytics API so tools like app
figures you know maybe eventually
Revenue cat I don't know we'll have to
look at like exactly how useful this
would be for our customers to kind of
mix some level of data the challenge
though as always with Appstore analytics
is that they're always anonymized and
they're also always opt in and so it's
something I always keep in mind if
you're looking at App Store depends like
Financial reports and stuff like that
are not often I
like this is more of they like usage
analytics and stuff like this so like if
you're trying to find out like how many
active users do I have well you have to
go in and like some of that's anonymized
some of it isn't and there's little I
don't know you know I'm sure Ariel at
app figures is digging into this and has
already been using aspects of it but you
have to know which ones are opt in and
which ones are Global so some some of
the stats in app store analytics are
Global some are opt in and so you have
to look and then you look at the
percentage and it tells you like my
weather app had like 25% opin rate
launching in a pro had like 20% opt-in
rate so you have to take the number and
multiply it by the opt-in rate to get a
sense for what's going on because Apple
can't do division for you like whatever
I mean it's kind of important though if
somebody's gonna be looking at the
numbers and apple just multiplied it I
always thought that sure the audiences
aren't the same yeah yeah they don't
behave the same and then similarly Apple
added a ton of analytics in app store
connect and I think this was part of the
dma I think the dma like required them
to share more statistics with developers
so they added hundreds of new metrics to
apps or connect so there's a lot more
going on there nobody should ever need
more than a hundred
metrics I haven't looked at them but
like what do you need to know there's
like seven that matter anyway I'm glad
Reg has opened up the other
393 to us anyway another uh another
thing announced earlier this year that
seems to be kind of En closed beta is
contingent offers again another cool
opportunity this is one where and we've
seen some apps doing this so like
actually speaking of straa again Strava
is doing this thing now where they
promote other apps I don't know what
kind of deals they have with those apps
or if it's like a sponsorship a
partnership an affiliate or whatever but
with contingent pricing Strava could say
hey as part of your Strava membership
you get 20% off weather up and you can
bundle the pricing and this is going to
be at the App Store level and then the
cool thing there with contingent pricing
is that if somebody unsubscribes from
straa they're no longer had that
contingent pricing and so then their
pricing would go up on that next renewal
so Apple baking this in at the App Store
level again it's in beta right now so we
haven't seen it massively in use but
think there's a lot of opportunity here
for like affiliate deals I mean I'm
thinking about this for weather up like
when they open it broadly like what apps
can I work with where when somebody
signs up through a contingent offer they
get 20% off and then I give that app a
kickback and I think it's cross remember
free app of the day yeah it's still
that's still going on back in the day is
it a thing I thought I thought Apple
kind of banned it when they said like no
like pseudo app stores on the App Store
I don't know if it's the exact same site
but people will do this for ASO because
you get a massive search in downloads so
people will give like lifetime access
for free and things like that for a day
but yeah used to I mean cross per has
always been good I think this feature as
I understand it's going to be more
targeted at people that can do big bis
Dev deals so it's going to be like
larger apps probably take advantage of
this but still another arrow in the
quiver for us Y and then we've got some
bigger things to dive into offers
streamline purchasing store kit views
inap purchase testing enhan ments but
last small thing is they actually
mentioned this in one of those wwc
videos and I think a lot of people don't
even realize this exists apple offers
support via phone or email in nine
languages
247 this always reminds me of the
technical support incidents that like
people forget exists like you can get
code level support from Apple with these
two free technical incidents every year
that like nobody uses and then people
talk about I can never get a hold of
Apple you know whatever they offer phone
support I've called them before about
like changing an address or something
like that and I thought it was
interesting that Apple mentioned this in
that wwc video I think because so few
people actually use it and they really
do want to help more developers via this
channel so it's kind of cool that they
do that and then that they specifically
called it out in a wwec video this isn't
like technical code support this is like
I have a problem with App Store connect
I need to change my business address or
something like that right okay yeah yeah
it's App Store connect support but the
technical incident still exists and
again it's like I feel people know about
that this is a separate resource but if
you need code level support from Apple
you have two technical incidents a year
that you can use like look at up I would
just always I feel like whenever that
would come to mind well a lot of times
it would be like you're dealing with app
riew and I don't think they help in that
department typically appu has their own
escalation methods yeah but I'm was like
I'm not going to call these App Store
connect people did this to me I'm not
going to call them they just going to do
more of it to me but I'm sure they're
helpful in in some cases so yeah good
let's talk about wiback offers and I
know Jacob you've been doing a deep dive
on that do you want me to give the
overview or you want yeah I mean I yeah
I can talk I can give you a break David
so so yeah winback offers so yet another
kind of offer so it's the fourth the
fourth offer is it fourth but how do we
count for so intro offers there be like
free trials and introductory offers
there's promo offers which are like
basically anytime you're in your app
and then now we have winback offers no
but offer codes offer codes you have an
offer code wait then what's what is the
thing where you can put an app in
promoted when you can put an iip into
the app store oh that's totally separate
because that's yeah it's separate but I
think it also has the word promoted so
like technically not related but they've
got some branding organization issues
but anyway we got four types of offers
now yeah yeah so anyway so intros are
like free trials is the big one but then
you can also have like the first time
somebody starts a subscription in a
group you can give them like a cheaper
deal so that's one option those you can
only have one or none on any
subscription product within a group I
believe right and it's you only get it
once within the group but each product
can have a different so one could have a
free trial one could be 30% off
something like this promotional offers
can be applied at any time in a person's
active cycle so like if they have a
active subscription you can apply it to
that and reduce the price of that offer
I think you can actually do it to a new
subscription as well but there's some
stuff there where you have to have it
signed by a server like it's this really
kind of somewhat overly complicated
process but it is possible those
promotional offers and now we have
winback offers and so winback offers are
basically very similar to the first two
categories but they apply to folks who
had a subscription and it is now lapsed
which is something that wasn't really
obviously easy with the existing
promotional offers and so now not only
is this a new category of offer it
actually has some new functionality to
it that's unique to the other so one you
can actually set who this applies to
in appstore connect I haven't seen the
demo but it's like basically you have
some selectors on like this can apply to
these laps subscribers so you set it
there and then what a couple things
happen so one you now see this in the
auto renewal status field on their store
kit 2 response like you'll see like
eligible winback offers as an array that
comes back from some of the store kit 2
responses but then there's some other
things so another place you'll be able
to optionally see this is on when they
open the app they can actually get a
popup which this is kind of huge so like
you can turn on this win back offer
somebody opens the app and like app
store will automatically pop a modal
that's like hey you're eligible for this
which is actually pretty powerful the
other place you can see it is on the App
Store and this is kind of cool what did
they call this seamless purchasing David
what was the name of it streamline
purchasing streamline purchasing so on
the app store Page like they'll have it
there as a winback offer and they can
purchase it which like I guess you could
see somebody like wandering over the
page Maybe maybe they uninstall the app
they go back to reinstall it and it's
there I'm not so sold on that being well
we'll get to the efficacy predictions
and then I guess similarly inside the
app they have in their own store kit
views and like you'll have programmatic
access to any eligible winback offers
you can decide like how those are
displayed but like the accessibility is
controlled from the Apple side now
that's cool I think some things that
make this a little less effective and
powerful than like it could be or like
what we traditionally think about
winback offers are like a very powerful
thing for like reactivating and raising
your LTV because like there's a lot of
customers they'll subscribe for a while
they stop using the app they're life
moved on but they already know who you
are they've already spent money you know
they have the need right so marketing to
that group can be a really just an easy
lift for your Revenue but one of the
problems I see with wiback offers is
like there's still no way to communicate
with these folks oh wait Charlie am I
wrong so there is they didn't go super
into detail but in their session they
did say there is a way to generate an
offer link that you can distribute your
own way now sure my understanding is you
have to perfectly match their
eligibility criteria or you could send
somebody a link that they're not
eligible for right yeah they talked
about this in the session it was like
you can create this link and then like
share it on social and it's like well if
you share it on social you would need to
say like if and this gets into the
eligibility because what you want to do
is be like here's a winb back offer list
of people make them eligible for a thing
also communicate directly to that group
of people like here's a thing you're
eligible for and again I think apples
they're a little tied around their own
feet here because by privacy stuff and
all that crap they can't really do this
but it really like hamstrings like how
powerful and it's frustrating because
they have the information they know the
people they could even possibly be like
hey if somebody's opted in to push in
the past or whatever let me send them an
apple branded marketing reactivation
thing if they've oped in obviously
that's a bigger ask but anyway it's
still something but I still think that
makes it less than as powerful as it
could be for most developers there's
another one too which they kind of
briefly mentioned they said that the
editorial team may feature your winback
offer across the App Store in the today
tab well but like in a personalized way
so you would I'm guessing it's I didn't
write that quote I missed that if they
said that but I was wondering the same
thing is like will show to eligible
people from what I understand the App
Store is now actually very much a Tik
Tock style feed in a way that apple is
doing like user level personalization on
like lots of the pages now so yeah it's
like if the person is eligible it may
pop up in their today feed as part of it
if they're eligible and they go to the
app tab it can show up in line along
with the rest of the like categories and
stuff in the app tab so I I mean I think
this is really cool this is like apple
kind of again helping developers make
more money helping themselves make more
money along the way but like giving
developers and the cool thing about this
one is that it's like you just configure
a few things in app store connect and
like it's done so like yeah is it in and
of itself the way it's currently built
going to be this massive lift no but
it's like you spend 10 minutes filling
this out and apple promotes it and it
shows up in the App Store when
somebody's searching and a perent or two
you pay in complexity right so now you
have this like thing if it's not that
effective it's like not a program you
want to be like thinking about running
so here let me give the be case here
that like you have to be opening the app
to see it no because you see it on the
App Store because apple on the okay but
still like contriving we don't actually
know how much that's going to be visible
and stuff like that because like every
other app that has a win back is going
to be competing for that same space
right right maybe that happens whatever
but like you have to like open the app
so like who is this now it's somebody
who has churned but is's still actively
using the app which at that point I can
just like make you see my pay wall right
like I'm already got you right like I
don't necessarily need this and again
like the thing that makes winback offers
so powerful in the wild is that you've
got marketing channel access to these
people you send them an email or a push
notification or something like that
that's what makes wiback so powerful
again it's like apple gets like close
but then they just like Miss like the
like fundamental thing that makes
something powerful right and well I'm
I'm going to be begging Apple for a
server to server notification when
somebody becomes eligible because that
would be really powerful cuz then like
we at Revenue cas or individual
developers could then send that push
notification when you get the server to
server that somebody becomes eligible
but still you were talking about
complexity and there's actually not that
much complexity to support this because
it uses the same thing as promotional
offers talking about the technical
complexity I'm just like now you have to
remember like oh yeah I've got this win
back offer running and like who gets hit
and who doesn't get it maybe it's minor
maybe it's fine and and having it all be
like basically for free with App Store
connect if your app has subscription
like that's pretty cool and you don't
have to do like the jws authentication
and like the promotional offers is a
great feature but it's like not been
adopted like we at R really should do
more work on promotional offers to make
it way easier because it is really
powerful yeah but this is like the baby
step for anybody can just set it up and
it's way easier and then in an email
support or whatever you can use these
custom links and like it's a nice step
in the right direction and making it way
easier for developers yeah I suppose if
you had a really broad targeting Charlie
what were you gonna say I was just going
to say functionally it's just like
introductory offers like it feels like
when you set up a trial it's almost like
it's not an afterthought because it's
strategically that's way more important
but they're really simple to set up it's
just a drop- down editor that looks very
similar to that and then you just kind
of have it and especially if the
editorial stuff is real like that's a
new entry point in your funnel right
yeah yeah well yeah I'll concede it's
better than nothing but we'll
see interesting at least I think it's
got us Revenue cat inspired to like lean
into promo offers a little bit more we
been talking about today and slack and I
think there's a lot of stuff that we
could do we've already been working on
some stuff related to this but like it's
given us some good ideas about how
because you know again with us because
of the Privacy domain that we operate
within like we have a bit more like
individually identify like we can
connect Who's got what subscription to
like a person or like to a push
notification token or like whatever so
we can connect them that lets us do like
you could see a world where in Revenue
cat you create an offer just like you
would do here we with promo offer
instead of with a winback offer but then
we also have like the list so we can
help you actually communicate to that
set of customers I think that's actually
where most of the leverage comes from in
these winback campaigns yep so anyway
nice job Apple we'll do
better free money you know if it's one
or two% lift in a year it's free and
cheap and not super complex to implement
so I think it's great and if Apple does
create a server to server notification
for this then it becomes even more
powerful in that for way less effort
than promotional offers you'd be able to
set up targeting and send out
notifications and stuff so super cool
and then we touched on it briefly but
the Streamline purchasing is interesting
that people can actually do the full
transaction on the App Store so the app
pay sheet will come up on the App Store
and they're like paying on the App Store
watching the session it was interesting
you can turn this off and actually I
don't know if it's opt in or opt out I
think it's opt
in it's opt out okay so I believe so so
when you set it up it will automatically
allow people to purchase in the app
store if you don't want that you can
show them the offer in the app store or
apple will show them the offer in the
app store and then when they tap the
button it actually goes to your app
where then you can provide a customized
experience so if you are creating those
something to keep in mind decide whether
you want to opt in or opt out to this
streamline purchasing all right we are
at the
hour this has been going I think that's
all the major stuff there's a couple
little things on there we didn't talk
about but there's a bunch of impr to
store kit views which is cool and some
stuff that on in app purchase testing
enhancements but you all use Revenue K
you don't need this crap well but use
storit configuration files I gotta make
Josh Holtz happy because that's his
that's his thing but like anybody who's
using Revenue cat or not for any storit
stuff you should be using storit
configuration files to test everything
and they made it better this year that's
the short answer yeah exactly two last
things I did want to touch on briefly
Apple announced this thing called
Advanced Commerce
apis and there's not a lot of
information on this yet but in the
announcement it says that and for those
on the podcast I'm doing air quotes
complex monetization use cases and so
the examples they gave was content
creator apps with Creator subscriptions
that's currently a huge pain and we get
tons of customers coming to revenue cat
can you solve this in a way that the App
Store doesn't the answer is no because
Apple doesn't support it so apple is
specifically saying they're working on
this to allow
looking for partners there's a form that
we can link maybe in the yeah you can
sign up to get notified and it sounds
like it's going to be a little bit more
of a white glove kind of thing but the
way I read it and there's other examples
complex skew bundling digital content
across multiple apps in the same
developer account the announcement kind
of read like apple recognizes and
probably has recognized for years that
there's all these complex use cases that
the App Store does not currently support
with the standard subscript I and Ina
purchases and this is them saying okay
we're going to start allowing broader
monetization options on the App Store
maybe they've finally realized that
their Monopoly on purchasing has led to
some negative consequences and it's time
for them to like kind of do what any
other purchasing API would allow you to
do which is good if this is like
Downstream dma stuff like I'm very happy
like I'm I'm now Pro dma because like
this has been just a problem we've
needed for a long time I mean we get so
many requests at Revenue cat like
they're never like I mean there are some
huge examples of apps doing this and I
think they've gotten a little bit of
wink and not help from Apple to make it
happen but like there's a ton of small
apps that would benefit from trying to
do some cool stuff here there's just
like a lot of apps I think there a blog
post about this somewhere like the apps
that don't exist there's a lot of apps
that don't exist because the stuff is
too hard and hopefully like they'll
start with like some development
partners and then they'll bring it down
and open it up to more people but I
think that would be very good I am all
for more business opportunity on the App
Store and this is like you know with
apple I continually get my hopes up and
then get let down but this those things
it's like they're moving forward with
like Shing model and new monetization
and like up on this link to be notified
I'm I'm gonna like put all my emails in
in that box because I want to know
what's going on and then the last thing
I did want to touch on is ADD
attribution kit we're going to do a blog
post on this Eric sufer already wrote a
great blog post on this but it's kind of
SK ad Network 2.0 it's new and it has
some nice things it seems a little more
from the developer experience
perspective it's a little more under
like rockable I watched the session on
it it made more to me than skn yeah but
it was kind of like a small Evolution
like there's some new features but it's
fundamentally the same thing like
fundamentally same thing it's just like
maybe the DX is a little bit better and
they fixed a few things um y but I was
hoping it with the Rebrand it would be
like all new and like new capabilities
and like the kind of contribution
framework everybody's kind of been
hoping Apple would build this is not
quite that but it's newer features and
better and whatever but hey I think one
of SK no like we're never going to get
back to the attribution world we were in
and like Apple's clear like if you want
to do attribution you have to run it
through us which is like a little crazy
but that's the rule they've thrown down
I do think the DX matters I think like
SK ad networks like abstractions were
weird like it didn't make sense in a lot
of cases those are still in the new ad
attribution kit but I do feel like it's
a little bit more friendly the
frustrating part though and this is like
with pretty much all Apple announcements
is that from my reading of it is that
like most of the features require at
least 17.4 iOS 17.4 iPad OS 17.4 but
then some of the new features like one
of the big new features is re-engagement
so you can actually specifically because
what's happened in the past is like you
just run a bunch of ads and sad network
doesn't know whether or not they had
previously installed the app previously
engaged so they just show as if they're
a net new user well that's not good you
want to understand like who's been
remarketed to and re-engaged versus like
who's a net new user so this
re-engagement stuff is actually really
cool and that's kind of the biggest I
think announcement for ad attribution
kit but that requires iOS 18 so it's
like okay maybe in
2028 I mean thankfully people have been
upgrading quickly I saw sat recently 77%
of people are now on iOS 17 or later so
it's good think IOS as a platform people
do move quickly to update but when 20 to
30% of folks a year in are still not on
the latest version it sucks that all
these fun new things aren't Backward
Compatible I wish Apple would find a way
to do what Google does and be able to
backport some of these new things
because now at attribution kit maybe
2025 and six like Facebook starts really
ramping up with it like they still
haven't even fully ramped with esad
network so anyways we'll do a deeper
dive maybe even do a podcast with Eric
sufer to kind of unpack all of this in
more detail but something to be on the
lookout for and to know it exists even
if we're not going to go into all the
details here on this webinar podcast but
I think that's about it it that's
everything it was kind of light honestly
for dubdub like there's enhancements we
were kind of going into this with this
assumption at least on the stor kid side
because of I think all the resources
that probably put into dma compliance
the last 6 months like probably took a
lot of oxygen out of the room for
working on App Store stuff I don't have
any inside information on that but you
have to think it's not like apple
they're human they only have so many
resources and so many threads they can
run on at a given time so I wasn't
surprised to kind of see incremental
good stuff but not like a big revolution
this year in on the Commerce side so
which it's kind of nice sometimes when
it's quiet at least for me and my
business it's nice when they don't
totally totally turn everything upside
down so yeah we can focus more on
promotionals and other fun things this
year instead of like all new storit 3 or
something all right thanks everybody for
coming thanks
everybody thanks so much for listening
if you have a minute please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player
you can also stop by chat. sub club.com
to join our private community
[Music]